# ORION WILLS

## Data Scientist



512-992-5002



orion.wills@gmail.com in // /in/orion-wills/ /orion-wills/





## **Professional Bio**

Orion is a problem solver with a talent for answering challenging questions in an actionable manner. He is an excellent team leader with the unique ability to find solutions and deliver them in a meaningful way to stakeholders. Orion has twenty years of consultative client-facing experience and now data science. Soft skills have always been a strength.

## Technical Skills

Applied Statistics - SQL - Python - pandas - Numpy - Matplotlib - Seaborn - scikit-learn - Machine Learning - Natural Language Processing - Distributed Data - Data Storytelling - Git - Jupyter Notebooks -Anaconda - Critical Thinking - Problem Solving - Stakeholder Communication

# **Data Projects**

## **NLP Project**

Analyzed hundreds of Github README files and found differences between README contents and the dominant language the repository was written in. Used multiple classification methods (Bag of Words, Logistic Regression, PCA, and SVT) to predict language repo was written with.

## **Time Series Project**

Analyzed FitBit data to predict missing two-weeks worth of data. Used multiple scikit-learn algorithms including Facebook Prophet to accurately predict gender, height, weight, and motive for subject.

## **Anomaly Detection**

Analyzed Codeup's curriculum access logs and found anomalies in access to the curriculum post-graduation. Using IP addresses, detected what companies the individuals worked for as well as which cohort they belonged to.

## Clustering

Used multiple clustering algorithms to predict customer churn on a telco dataset based MRR, customer tenure, customer age, and services.

#### **Zillow Zestimate**

Used clustering and regression algorithms to predict and improve upon Zillow's predicted home sale prices.

#### **Sales Dashboard**

Created a dynamic sales dashboard for sales managers to monitor critical KPIs in Excel and **VBA** 

# **Professional Experience**

#### Oak Creek Homes

03/2017 - 08/2018

## Marketing Specialist

Successfully managed development of innovative online marketing strategies including website development content messaging, search engine optimization, local advertising with individual dealerships, and oversight of paid vendor partnerships for successful marketing campaigns.

Mattress Firm 03/2016 - 02/2017

## Store Manager

Promoted to Mega Center Store Manager, in spite of being the least tenured salesperson, with responsibility for daily store operations, sales and account management with proactive engagement and nurturing of clientele to identify any opportunities for expansion of services or products. Managed everything from new customer sales, inventory, branding, and daily citywide reporting.

**Able Lending** 02/2015 - 11/2015

#### Director of Sales

Led daily operations for sales team of sixteen Sales Representatives with oversight of sales and promotional initiatives to increase loan originations and fundings as well as to provide optimal customer service. Worked with product teams, marketing department, as well as underwriting to increase the scope of potential borrowers as well as increase prospect to application originations.

Yodle, Inc 04/2010 - 07/2014

## Area Sales Manager

Directed a sales teams with oversight of sales, business development, account management, staff training and performance management focused on optimizing sales and customer service. Successfully lead the top team in the company for eighteen months which also assisting in the development of tools to benefit the sales department.

# **EDUCATION**

**Codeup** 02/2019 - 06/2019

San Antonio, TX

Fully-immersive, project-based 18-week Data Science career accelerator that provides students with 600+ hours of expert instruction in applied data science. Students develop expertise across the full data science pipeline (planning, acquisition, preparation, exploration, modeling, delivery), and become comfortable working with real, messy data to deliver actionable insights to diverse stakeholders.